<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-08-03T16:54:14+05:30</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Green In You</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">A personal story, a wake up call, a call to action</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2020-07-25-a-wake-up-call" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="A personal story, a wake up call, a call to action" /><published>2020-07-14T05:30:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-07-14T05:30:00+05:30</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/A-wake-up-call</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2020-07-25-a-wake-up-call">&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t a clue who I was. And, like many others, I’ve always felt a desperation to know and be more of myself. When the world came to a staggering halt this year, I witnessed some clarity. The pandemic had me live alone in a five bedroom apartment – no roommates, let alone very many people to spare in our student town. So every morning I’d head to a trail nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within the stream which ran parallel to it, there were three rocks. The third rock, also the biggest, also right in the middle of the stream, was my literal sweet spot. There I sat for an hour everyday in the midst of nature. On the canopy of trees overhead, several times I’d spot the most gorgeous birds. So many intriguing insects everywhere and sometimes, they’d even crawl up onto me, chase me – yes, I got chased by a big, fat bumble bee! There were days when I got lucky, and deer, foxes, groundhogs, would sneak up on me. The stream’s babbling was tranquilizing. I felt one with everything around me, I felt utterly included. For the first time in my life, I experienced the presence of a safe space to be myself, because every being around me too – the trees, the birds, the animals, the insects – were also just being their true selves. They were awake and alert, they seemed truly alive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see, I had a lot of time to let loose and express myself authentically. Nature gave me that space free from the shackles of our made-up world. In the human world, I had been trying harder than ever to emulate anyone society upheld, I felt a fake. What this time has brought is a whole new paradigm. I cannot exaggerate harder how us humans are more a part of nature than we are above it or apart from it. I’m writing to you, because I want to tell you that you too have the capacity to transcend the insecurities of yourself, and proudly embody your reality, your being, just like nature naturally does.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s my affirmation that our path to deep satisfaction and a life thoroughly, happily lived lies closer to wilderness than our human social and economic bubbles. Which is why here I am, trying to sound the alarm – nature as we’ve known since the beginning of humankind’s journey is dying. Blatant disregard for nature’s plight leads nowhere, but the perish of our own sanity and of course, the perpetuity of our existence. This message is also a call to action. Through Green In You, I’ve been able to realign my lifestyle. As much satisfaction I feel relieving nature from the pervasiveness of the sheer abundance of my clothing, I feel pride. Every day our team is working very hard to bring you and your loved ones the same chance to make a difference. There’s a lot that can be done and we want to help you start with your closet.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tanisha Ghorpade</name></author><summary type="html">I hadn’t a clue who I was. And, like many others, I’ve always felt a desperation to know and be more of myself. When the world came to a staggering halt this year, I witnessed some clarity. The pandemic had me live alone in a five bedroom apartment – no roommates, let alone very many people to spare in our student town. So every morning I’d head to a trail nearby.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Times have changed, so should we</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2020-05-20-times-have-changed-so-should-we" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Times have changed, so should we" /><published>2020-05-20T15:32:34+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-20T15:32:34+05:30</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/times-have-changed-so-should-we</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2020-05-20-times-have-changed-so-should-we">&lt;p&gt;I’ve observed second-hand clothing is still visualized as ragged, dirty clothing. This image may have been true in the past when apparel was purchased by the customer and then disposed after rigorous use. However, today, people’s shopping habits have extensively changed because of stimuli from the fashion giants. The fashion industry nurtures consumerism. They introduced fast-fashion where brands like H&amp;amp;M, Forever21 and Zara among others have as many as 52 seasons in a year. This is far off from the initial three seasons brands had, in which styles would change as per the summer, winter and monsoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since companies churn out brand new styles about 52 times a year people feel “out-of-fashion” quickly and desire new clothing. This trend has been going on long enough for it to have become a habit, and now the customer is looking forward to changes much sooner. Therefore, unlike previous times, clothing gets discarded not because it is ragged, but simply because people are bored of it, it’s out of style, or a ton of new clothing has left no space in the closet for the not-so-old clothes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If these barely used clothes are still in their prime condition, they really should not be thrown away, causing catastrophic environmental damage. Instead, we should work to get rid of the stigma present and normalise reusing clothes. Sustainable fashion is not just for the low socio-economic class; it is for every conscious individual who
wants to appreciate and enjoy fashion in harmony with nature!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Times have changed, so should we.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tanisha Ghorpade</name></author><summary type="html">I’ve observed second-hand clothing is still visualized as ragged, dirty clothing. This image may have been true in the past when apparel was purchased by the customer and then disposed after rigorous use. However, today, people’s shopping habits have extensively changed because of stimuli from the fashion giants. The fashion industry nurtures consumerism. They introduced fast-fashion where brands like H&amp;amp;M, Forever21 and Zara among others have as many as 52 seasons in a year. This is far off from the initial three seasons brands had, in which styles would change as per the summer, winter and monsoon.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">When the impossible becomes possible</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2020-04-19-when-the-impossible-becomes-possible" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="When the impossible becomes possible" /><published>2020-04-19T15:32:34+05:30</published><updated>2020-04-19T15:32:34+05:30</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/when-the-impossible-becomes-possible</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:4000/posts/2020-04-19-when-the-impossible-becomes-possible">&lt;p&gt;It was 1907, and synthetic plastic was invented. However, it was only later until the
1930s during the industrial era that plastic was commercially, widely available. I think
when it comes to plastic, there are a multitude of seemingly impossible possibilities. The
first of course was its transformative invention. A substance like never before-
chemically inert, water-resistant, insulates well, doesn’t break easily and is cheap to
produce. No doubt, these characteristics were quick to kickstart man’s love affair with
plastic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Within only one human lifetime, before we knew it, plastic was virtually everywhere. No,
not only in every household on the planet but literally everywhere we have ever looked.
According to Dickinson the author of Planet Plastic, plastic today is in the Arctic and the
Antarctic, and also in the middle of the Pacific. It is in our drinking water, the ocean’s
greatest depths, the soil, the air we breathe and even in entire food chains. Every human
being today ingests about 2000 particles of microplastic each week of their lives. This
quantity is comparative to eating a whole credit card on a weekly basis. What’s more, is
that greater than half the plastic that was ever created came into being only since 2002!
Who would have even thought plastic would take over our world so drastically, such that
the World Economic Forum warned it’s likely there will be more plastic in our oceans
than actual fish by weight in the year 2050?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I care deeply about the well-being of the planet and all its habitants. The plastic pollution
problem today threatens not only my ability to live in a healthy, stable environment but
that of every generation to come because of the forever substance that plastic has been
built to be. Besides, it’s utterly unnerving how the lack of research about the
toxicological effects of plastic is the only factor keeping us from unveiling a host of
adverse health impacts within that pandora’s box!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, I staunchly advocate for what Theodore Roosevelt said, “Natural resources are
assets which must be turned over to the next generation increased and not impaired in
value”. However, solving the magnanimous plastic problem before irreversible negative
impacts take place, seems nearly impossible to me. But I will still then, nurture
confidence in myself and every other conscious individual who dares to care. Because, I
know, that every now and then the seemingly impossible becomes possible through just a
flash of discovery, revealing new potentials and revolutions like never before!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tanisha Ghorpade</name></author><summary type="html">It was 1907, and synthetic plastic was invented. However, it was only later until the 1930s during the industrial era that plastic was commercially, widely available. I think when it comes to plastic, there are a multitude of seemingly impossible possibilities. The first of course was its transformative invention. A substance like never before- chemically inert, water-resistant, insulates well, doesn’t break easily and is cheap to produce. No doubt, these characteristics were quick to kickstart man’s love affair with plastic.</summary></entry></feed>